From the dark side to our side.
Hellboy is a fantasy, action film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
In the final days of World War II, the Nazis attempt to
use black magic to aid their dying cause.
The Allies raid the camp where the ceremony is taking place, but not before they
summon a baby demon who is rescued by Allied forces and dubbed "Hellboy".
Sixty years later, Hellboy serves the cause of good rather than evil as an agent in the Bureau of Paranormal Research & Defense, along with
Abe Sapien - a merman with psychic powers, and Liz Sherman - a woman with pyrokinesis, protecting America against dark forces.
Hellboy, played by Ron Perlman.
Elizabeth 'Liz' Sherman, played by Selma Blair.
Abraham 'Abe' Sapien, played by Doug Jones.
Prof. Trevor 'Broom' Bruttenholm, played by John Hurt.
John Myers, played by Rupert Evans.
Tom Manning, played by Jeffrey Tambor.
Hellboy is a 2004 American superhero film based on the Dark
Horse Comics character, created by Mike Mignola.
Written and directed by Guillermo del Toro, it is the first
live-action film in the Hellboy franchise.
Ron Perlman stars as the titular character, alongside Selma Blair,
Jeffrey Tambor, Karel Roden, Rupert Evans, and John Hurt.
The film draws inspiration from the debut comic Hellboy: Seed of Destruction.
In the film, a charismatic demon-turned-investigator named "Hellboy" works with the secretive Bureau of Paranormal Research and Defense to
suppress paranormal threats, when a resurrected sorcerer seeks to make Hellboy fulfill his destiny by triggering the apocalypse.
Hellboy had its premiere at the Mann Village Theater in Los Angeles on March
30, 2004, and was released in the United States on April 2.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $99.8
million against a production budget between $60–66 million.
The film was followed by a sequel, Hellboy II: The
Golden Army, in 2008, and two reboots.
The film explores themes of nazi, sacrifice,
superhero, paranormal phenomena, black magic.
The tone is dark.